Andrew Klapper

Customer service and sales professional. I sold my freight brokerage business about 2.5 years ago to study software-engineering. I am looking to start a position where I can use my current sales and customer service experience to help others, build a positive reputation within a tech based company, and look for upward mobility in a web development based position.

2152 Sedalia CT SE Marietta, Ga 30067

☐ (470) 927-7864



ak475826@gmail.com

GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Shipping Services & Logistics LLC MC# 1120472, Marietta, Ga - Owner

Sept 2019 - Jan 2022

I owned and operated a freight brokerage that focused on dry bulk commodities, personal autos, and heavy equipment. The applicable skills were a strong base in sales to acquire customers, customer service to retain them, teamwork with the drivers executing the loads, and real time problem solving to resolve issues that could arise from either party. I decided to change career paths in 2022 because the difference between working for and owning a freight brokerage was drastically different and I was unhappy with the 20 hour days, 7 days a week.

Woodstock Developers Group, Woodstock, Ga

Jan 2023 - PRESENT

Instructor lead programming with focus on enterprise level software design using simple concepts. We have weekly in-person and virtual meetings which involve pair programming, SCRUM AGILE methodology while rotating the role of scrum master, working as a team to meet deadlines, and other real world industry best practices for software development life-cycle.

BGDK, Marietta, Ga - O BGDK - SGame

Ian 2023 - PRESENT

Main portfolio project for Woodstock Developers Group. The project is built using: MonoRepo – Using NX to scale UI/UX Projects. RESTful APIs – Written in Typescript, running on Express servers. Single Page Applications (SPAs) – Using React & React Router an efficient, responsive, and easy to use UI with MUI Material–UI seamless response to screen size and shape. Modular design – Utilizing NX to share common libraries between UI and service layer. Design Patterns – Dynamic endpoints, context, command, and chain of responsibility (CoR,) state machine., builder/factory, and others. Google Cloud – Deployed using App Engine, Firebase, Cloud SQL. You can see the source code and deployed app using the links (BGDK, Game) above.

FreeCodeCamp, Structy - (A) FreeCodeCamp Structy Repo

Dec 2021 - PRESENT

I started learning with FreeCodeCamp and many other free online resources. The 3 I find most helpful are FreeCodeCamp, Strictly, and Harvard CS50. They each have their own style and provide a concise and curriculum for the service they provide. The above links are to my FCC profile with certifications and list of completed lessons, as well as, the GitHub Repo of my Structy practice algorithms. I understand data structures, sorting, Big-O, and many computer science concepts and theory at an intermediate level. I would love to use the problem solving, teamwork, active learning, communication, adaptability, and programming skills I have gained, and will gain, to use for your clients and teams.

COMMUNITY

Volunteering Mentoring & Involvement -

EDUCATION

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, Ga-Professional Sales

Ian 2004 - Dec 2006

Completed 29 credits toward BA in professional sales

SKILLS

TypeScript React.js Node.js Python

Generative AI w/ Gemini models

- Text
- Audio
- Video

PostgreSQL MongoDB

Git

REST API's

OOP Design Patterns

TDD w/ Jest

Linux

Windows

MacOs

Google Cloud

Discord & Slack

1 of 2 tests complete for CompTia A+ Certifications

LANGUAGES

English - Native

Spanish - Fluent

Professional References

Ryan McGuinness: 303-242-45757 cell - Google Cloud Solutions Architect, Instructor for WDG - Years Known 1.5

Tim Liberman: 470-456-0172 cell - Network Engineer Boldyn - Years Known 18